KELVIN A. LAGOTA

+1 514 993 2605

2-151 Woodland Dr., Peterborough, ON, K9L 1N7 kelz.lagota@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Professional Teaching Experience, post-secondary level: Since 2008

Research Experience: 2008 - 2020

Administrative Work Experience: 2011 - 2015

Current employment status

Trent University (Part-time Professor), since January 2024 Fleming College (Part-time Professor), since April 2023 Dawson College (Continuing Education faculty), since January 2018

Immigration Status

Permanent Resident in Canada Filipino citizen

WORK HISTORY

January 2024 - present

Trent University - Part-time Professor Course taught: Math for Teachers: Statistics

April 2023 - present

Fleming College - Frost Campus - Part-time Professor
Course taught: Applied Calculations for Heavy Equipment Operator

January 2018 - present

Dawson College - Part-time Faculty (Continuing Education)

Courses taught: Linear Algebra, Calculus 1 (Science), Calculus 1 (Social Science), Calculus 2 (Science), Business Mathematics, Financial Calculations, Remedial Activities for Secondary IV Math, Remedial Activities for Secondary V Math, Applied Mathematics for Computer Science

January 2021 - January 2023

University of the Philippines Diliman - Part-time Senior Lecturer

Courses taught: College Algebra, Trigonometry, Calculus 2, Calculus 3, Differential Equations and Applications

September 2015 - December 2019

Concordia University - Grad Student Instructor, Tutor, Teaching Assistant Courses taught: Algebra and Functions, Differential and Integral Calculus 2

November 2008 - July 2015

University of the Philippines Diliman - Instructor (Full-time)

Courses taught: Algebra, Trigonometry, Precalculus, Calculus 1, Calculus 2, Calculus 3, Differential Equations and Applications

June 2011 - July 2015

University of the Philippines Diliman

Coordinator for National Service Training Program - College of Science

EDUCATION

September 2015 - December 2019

Ph.D. Mathematics

Concordia University

Thesis: "Green function and self-adjoint Laplacians on polyhedral surfaces"

Supervisors: Alexey Kokotov, PhD and Victor Kalvin, PhD

August 2011 - May 2015

Ph.D. Mathematics (Withdrawn, transferred to Concordia U) University of the Philippines Diliman

November 2008 - May 2011

M.S. Mathematics

University of the Philippines Diliman

Thesis: "Symmetric Expressions M of order 2n with Essential

Spectrum and Deficiency index d(M)=n+3"

Supervisor: Marian P. Roque, PhD

June 2005 - October 2008

B.S. Mathematics

University of the Philippines Diliman

Undergraduate Research: "On Approximation by Polynomials:

The Weierstrass Approximation Theorem"

Supervisor: Marian P. Roque, PhD

OTHER ACTIVITIES AND APPOINTMENTS

- Assistant Director, 14th Philippine Mathematical Olympiad
- ➤ Member, College of Science-NSTP Committee (2010-2015)
- ➤ Member, UPD-NSTP Executive Committee (2011-2015)
- Member of the local organizing committees of CIMPA School in Manila (2014) and SEAMS School in Manila (2011)
- Volunteer mentor at Diliman Learning Resource Center, UPD (2006-2008)

RESEARCH PUBLICATIONS

- A. Kokotov, K. Lagota, Green function and self-adjoint Laplacians on polyhedral surfaces, Canadian Journal of Mathematics, Vol. 72(5), (2020), pp. 1324-1351. doi: 10.4153/S0008414X1900033
- K. Lagota, On the domain of the adjoint Laplacian on a compact Riemann surface with conical singularities, Matimyas Matematika, Vol. 43, No. 1, (2020), pp.1-18.
- M.P. Roque, G. Limson, K. Lagota, Non Limit-Point Symmetric Differential Expressions with Essential Spectrum, Matimyas Matematika, Vol. 30, Nos. 2-3 (2007), pp. 85-93.

PRESENTATIONS IN CONFERENCES AND SYMPOSIA

- Self-adjoint Laplacians on a compact Riemann surface with conical singularities and their determinants, 2021 MSP¹ Annual Convention (virtual), May 2021
- > Symmetric Expressions of the Form $My=(-1)^ny^{(2n)}+(cx^6y^{(4)})^{(4)}-(x^5y''')'''+(x^2y')'$, (with MP Roque), 2012 MSP Annual Convention, De La Salle Lipa, Lipa City, Batangas, PHILIPPINES, May 2012
- > Symmetric Expressions M of order 2n with Essential Spectrum and Deficiency Index n+3, (with MP Roque), The 6th SEAMS-GMU² International Conference on Mathematics and Its Applications, Universitas Gadjah Mada, Yogyakarta, INDONESIA, 12-15 July 2011
- > Symmetric Expressions of the Form $My=(-1)^ny^{(2n)}+(cx^2y')'$, (with MP Roque), 2011 MSP Annual Convention, University of Santo Tomas, Manila, PHILIPPINES, May 2011
- Symmetric Expressions of order 2n with Essential Spectrum and Deficiency Index n+3, (with MP Roque), 2009 MSP Annual Convention, Limketkai, Cagayan De Oro, Misamis Oriental, PHILIPPINES, May 2009

SEMINARS, WORKSHOPS, AND SCHOOLS ATTENDED

- Focus Program Analytic Function Spaces and Their Applications, Fields Institute, Toronto, Canada, July – December 2021
- ➤ 2016 CRM Summer School on Spectral theory and applications, Laval University, Quebec, Canada, 4 14 July 2016
- CIMPA-NIMS³ Research School on dynamical systems: Examples, billiards and the 3-body problems, Center for Applications of Mathematical Principle, Daejeon, South Korea, 25 May – 3 June 2015
- *CIMPA-ICIAM-IMU-CDC-Philippines Research School 2014: Partial Differential Equations: Analysis, Numerics, and Applications to Flood and Tsunamis, Institute of Mathematics, University of the Philippines Diliman, 23 June 4 July 2014
- > SEAMS Manila School on the Applications of Algebra and Analysis, Institute of Mathematics UP Diliman, 4-15 April 2011

² Southeast Asian Mathematical Society – Gadjah Mada University

¹ Mathematical Society of the Philippines

³ Centre International de Mathematiques Pures et Appliquees – National Institute for Mathematical Sciences

⁴ http://www.cimpa-icpam.org/IMG/pdf/manila%202014 mr.pdf